# ANANYA SHETTY

ananyashetty994@gmail.com | +1(207)-766-6642 | San Francisco, CA | linkedin.com/in/ananyashetty157

# **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with experience in developing web and mobile applications. A passionate coder for usability and user experience with technical knowledge to create cool digital experiences. My experience includes programming languages such as ReactJS, AngularJS, C#, Java, MySQL, AWS, GCP, Bootstrap, jQuery.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Software Skills: Java, JavaScript, C, C#, Python, MS SQL, NodeJS, Typescript, jQuery.
- Tools: IntelliJ, Visual Studio 2015, SSMS 2014, AWS Services, Google Cloud Platform, Azure.
- Framework: SpringBoot, ASP.NET, AngularJs, ReactJS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Accenture Private Limited Solution**

Bangalore, India

**Application Development Analyst** 

Dec 2017 to June 2019

- Developed a model that collected more than 10,000-course data and was streamed to an artificial intelligence module that gave predictions on different skills important for a learner using python and MySQL.
- Handled and modified existing data model, stored procedures and Restful APIs to correct coding errors, upgraded interfaces and improved average performance by 35%.
- Scrum master for a team of 8 to deliver a major part of the project where the team had to change the skill of each employee to the skill recommended by Accenture.

#### **Accenture Private Limited Solution**

Bangalore, India

Application Development Associate

June 2016 to Nov 2017

- Designed and developed a web application that was used as a learning tool by more than 400K employees at Accenture using angularJs and ASP.Net.
- Accelerated goal to increase performance by more than 50% by moving the database from MSSQL to AWS services.

#### **EDUCATION**

 Master of Science - Computer Science University of San Francisco GPA: 3.56

Expected Graduation May 2021

• Bachelor of Engineering – Electronics and Communication GPA: 3.7 NMAMIT Nitte, Karnataka, India

August 2012 to May 2016

**PROJECTS** 

#### Batch Processing of Data using DataFlow and BigQuery

Jan 2020 to May 2020

- Process large (raw) data to produce meaningful, summarized data which involves manual data inspection, programmatic data cleanup & data manipulation, and analysis of the produced data.
- Worked on MapReduce framework and used Apache Beam Java SDK to develop a data processing pipeline that can efficiently process big data in cloud.
- Analyzed large, complex data using BigQuery and provide analytic insights, and Integrated various components & steps in cloud (data cleanup, data transformation, and data analytics) in order to complete an efficient, end-to-end data processing pipeline.

#### Distinct Caching Techniques on Raspberry Pi and connecting to the OS Kernel

Jan 2020 to May 2020

• Implementation and Performance Analysis of the 3 cache techniques:Direct Mapped Cache, Fully Associative Cache and Set Associative Cache.

## **Tourist Advisor Web Application**

Aug 2019 to Dec 2019

- Created a Travel Advisor App comprising of all hotel in Bay Area and corresponding reviews. The user can submit a review which can be edited/deleted.
- Developed this using Jetty Server/JDBC wherein users can explore different tourist spots with review of a particular tourist location using Expedia data and Google API.

### **USF Sports Club Web Application**

Aug 2019 to Dec 2019

• Created a Single Page Application using ReactJs and Java wherein users can explore different services provided by the sports club and register for any sport using Springboot and Reactjs as front end.

#### **Smart Traffic Controller**

Jan 2016 to Apr 2016

• Teamed in developing an automated traffic controller that captured the image of a lane in a junction that calculated the total number of vehicles on that lane, based varying signal timings.

#### **AWARDS**

- Received ACE (Accenture Celebrity Excellence) Individual award from Accenture Pvt. Ltd. for outstanding performance in the Financial year 2017-2018.
- Received the "Best Project of the year 2016" award for the Smart Traffic Controller project from the department.